Finding Aid for the Peggy Hamilton Adams Papers LSC.1373
UCLA Library Special Collections
Peggy Hamilton Adams papers
1911-1976
UCLA Library Special Collections
Adams, Peggy Hamilton
LSC.1373
29.0 linear feet (58 boxes and 57 oversize boxes)
Peggy Hamilton Adams was a fashion designer, editor of the Los Angeles Times rotogravure fashion page (1921-34) and a host for local radio programs (1929-33) that dealt with fashion concerns of the modern woman. The collection consists of materials related to Hamilton's career as designer, fashion editor, and socialite.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Peggy Hamilton Adams, bequest, 1984.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942302963606533
Biography
Born Mae Bedloe Armstrong, Hamilton began work as a costume designer; at Triangle film company, she designed for such stars as Mr. Julian Eltinge and Gloria Swanson; she worked at the Los Angeles Times as editor of its rotogravure fashion page (1921-34); known as Hollywood's dictator of fashions, she featured such celebrities as Gloria Swanson, Myrna Loy, Norma Shearer, Delores Del Rio, Joan Crawford, Betty Davis, and Greta Garbo posed in gowns by designers such as Adrian, Travis Banton, and Howard Greer; Hamilton promoted Los Angeles as the Paris of America in many fashion shows, including the first fasion show in an airplane (1928); she was appointed official hostess of Los Angeles County by then Supervisor Frank L. Shaw (1931) and was named Queen of Olympias of the Mythical Kindom of Olympia in an effort to publicize the 1932 Olympic Games; she hosted local radio programs (1929-33) dealing with fashion concerns of the modern woman.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of materials related to Hamilton's career as designer, fashion editor, and socialite. Includes paste-ups, scrapbooks, photographs, various issues of the Los Angeles Times fashion page, clippings, printed ads, radio scripts, and ephemera.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Peggy Hamilton Adams papers (478 items).
Online resources.; Mechanicals.; Scrapbooks.; Socialites -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Fashion editors -- Archives.; Photographs.; Adams, Peggy Hamilton--Archives.
- Beckman Fur Advertisements
  - Paste-ups and printed ads, 1930-1931. (Box 1)
- Los Angeles Times Fashion Page
  - Paste-ups, 1921. (Box 1)
  - Paste-ups, 1922. (Box 1)
  - Paste-ups, 1923. (Box 2)
  - Paste-ups, 1924, 1925 and 1927. (Box 2)
  - Paste-ups, 1926. (Box 3)
  - Paste-ups, 1928, 1930 and 1933. (Box 4)
  - Paste-ups, 1930. (Box 4, Box 5)
  - Various, 1929-1933. (Box 32)
  - Various Issues, 1932-1933. (Box 32)
  - Various Issues, January-June 1933 and July-December 1931. (Box 32)
  - Issues, (complete)., 1932 (Box 33)
  - Issues, (complete)., 1933 (Box 33)
  - Issues, (various)., 1933 (Box 33)
  - Issues, January-July 1925. (Box 34)
  - Paste-ups (boards), 1925. (Box 44)
  - Paste-ups (boards), July 1924. (Box 45)
- Los Angeles Times Fashion
  - Scrapbook, 1921. (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1921. (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1924. (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1925. (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1926. (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1927. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1928. (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1929. (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1930. (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook, 1931. (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933. (Box 16)
- Personal Photographs
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1931. (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933. (Box 18)
  - Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 18)
- Personal Memorabilia
  - Scrapbook, 1922. (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook, 1925. (Box 20)
- Fred Hamilton
  - Scrapbook, 1925. (Box 21)
- General
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1932. (Box 22)
  - Scrapbook, early 1940s. (Box 29)
  - Scrapbook, 1917. (Box 30)
  - Scrapbooks, n.d. (Box 31, 49)
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1932. (Box 49)
  - Scrapbooks, copy of celebrities, 1932. (Box 54)
  - Photographs. (Box 57)
- Fancy and Period Costumes
  - Scrapbook. (Box 31)
- Personal Appearances
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1932. (Box 23)
  - Scrapbook no.23, also hostess book no.2. (Box 26)
- Christmas Cards
  - Scrapbook. (Box 24)
- Trip to Europe
  - Scrapbook, 1924. (Box 25)
- Honeymoon Trip to East Coast
  - Scrapbook, diary, 1910-1911. (Box 27)
- Queen Olympia
  - Scrapbook, 1931. (Box 28)
- San Francisco Automobile Show, Fashion Pageant
  - Scrapbook, 1931. (Box 28)
- Orpheum Fashion Show
  - Scrapbook, 1938. (Box 29)
- General
  - 4 Scrapbooks, n.d. (Box 31)
- Radio Scripts
  - Scrapbook, 1929-1930. (Box 30)
  - Scrapbook--Radio scripts, primarily KHJ. (Box 30)
- Miscellaneous Newspapers
  - Miscellaneous newspapers. (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers and news clippings. (Box 35)
- Fashion
  - Drawings and photographs. (Box 36)
- Memorabilia
  - Key to city of San Francisco, January 27, 1931. (Box 46)
- PH's First Annual Biltmore Fashion Pageant
  - Posters, 1924. (Box 49)
- Miscellaneous
  - News clippings, printed papers, etc. (Box 37, Box 38)
  - News clippings. (Box 38 - 40, 43)
  - Photographs, news clippings, etc. (Box 41, Box 42, Box 43)
  - Scrapbook, ca. 1922-1924. (Box 49)
  - Talkback records (for sending messages via records) - 3 boxes. (Box 50)
  - News clippings, 1920s. (Box 51)
  - Magazines, news clippings. (Box 52)
  - Scrapbooks. (Box 53)
  - Scrapbook, magazines, letters, envelope of damaged photographs. (Box 55)
- 1932 Olympics
  - Photographs, clippings and memorabilia, 1932. (Box 56)
- Unarranged
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box 58 - 60, 76)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 61, 63 - 66, 68, 77, 79-81, 84-88, 91-92, 97-115)
  - Photographs and Miscellaneous (Box 62, 67, 69-75, 78, 82-83, 90, 98,)
  - Radio scripts, n.d. (Box 93, Box 94)
  - Radio scripts and Peggy mine sheet music (Box 95)
  - Radio scripts and film magazines (Box 96)